<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide Athlone</string>

    <!-- Category names -->
    <string name="category_events">Events</string>
    <string name="category_sights">Sights</string>
    <string name="category_food_drink"><![CDATA[Food & Drink]]></string>
    <string name="category_sleep">Sleep</string>

    <!-- Prices -->
    <string name="card_price">Price:</string>
    <string name="price_free">Free</string>
    <string name="sites_price_castle">€4 – €8pp</string>
    <string name="price_heal">€120</string>
    <string name="events_price_viking">€6 – €12</string>
    <string name="events_price_tri">€49 - €99</string>
    <string name="food_drink_price_karma">Club €5 - €20</string>
    <string name="food_drink_price_thyme">€5 - €30</string>
    <string name="food_drink_price_bistro">€4.50 - €29</string>
    <string name="stay_price_hodson">€41 - €90pps</string>
    <string name="stay_price_blu">From €60pp</string>
    <string name="stay_price_bandb">€50pp</string>
    <string name="stay_price_bay">€1 - €22</string>

    <!-- Place Names -->
    <string name="sites_name_church">Church of Saint Peter and Saint Paul</string>
    <string name="sites_name_castle">Athlone Castle</string>
    <string name="sites_name_gallery">Luan Gallery</string>
    <string name="sites_name_park"><![CDATA[Dún na Sí Amenity & Heritage Park]]></string>
    <string name="events_name_heal">Healing Weekend Workshop with Yuan Tze</string>
    <string name="events_name_viking">Viking Ship Tour</string>
    <string name="events_name_gallery">Elsewhere - Luan Gallery</string>
    <string name="evets_name_tri">TRIATHLONE 2017</string>
    <string name="food_drink_name_seans">Sean\'s Bar</string>
    <string name="food_drink_name_karma">The Prince Bar/Karma NightClub</string>
    <string name="food_drink_name_thyme">Thyme Restaurant</string>
    <string name="food_drink_name_bistro">Hatters Lane Bistro</string>
    <string name="stay_name_hodson"><![CDATA[Hodson Bay Hotel & Spa]]></string>
    <string name="stay_name_blu">Radisson Blu Hotel</string>
    <string name="stay_name_bandb"><![CDATA[Shelmalier House B&B]]></string>
    <string name="stay_name_bay">Galey Bay Camping</string>

    <!-- Place Description -->
    <string name="sites_description_church">This massive and extensively detailed church is a monumental statement on the confidence, power and the authority of the Roman Catholic Church in Ireland in the first decades after Independence. It is a superb essay in a Baroque style with various classical references, defined by strong horizontal lines and with planar layers of carefully designed facades. The whole composition, interior and exterior, is strongly handled with great mastery over spaces, materials and details. It is a triumph of twentieth century classicism by Ralph Byrne (1877–1946), a widely read architect who brought a range of international influences to create a unique fusion of historical style with a contemporary interpretation. Byrne was a very well respected architect of his day and was also responsible for the monumental cathedral in Mullingar (15310166) and the Church of the Four Masters in Donegal Town among other notable works. Byrne favoured the classical idiom for much of his church designs, moving away from the Gothic Revival-style, which had been en vogue since the early nineteenth-century for Roman Catholic building projects. The site of SS Peter and Paul was part of Custume Barracks until 1930 and previously housed an armour store and school house. The Roman Catholic Church built ordnance stores in Custume Barracks to compensate the military for this loss of site. This impressive church dominates the skyline of the west side of Athlone and contributes very significantly to the architectural heritage of the locale. However, this church seems slightly out of place in its riverside location facing the massive bulk of the medieval castle.</string>
    <string name="sites_description_castle">This 12th-century stone castle was built for King John by Bishop John de Gray of Norwich, designed to defend the crossing point of the river at Athlone. It’s located on the west side of Athlone Town, on the banks of the River Shannon. From its days as a timber fort, Athlone Castle evolved into a bold, defensive building with architectural features like the Keep of the Castle showcased as a dramatic backdrop to its diverse and fascinating story. Athlone Castle reopened in 2012 after extensive renovations; today the castle has been transformed into a multi-sensory experience in which family-friendly multimedia displays and interactive games guide visitors through its halls. The great Siege of Athlone is relived in a 360º cinematic experience, transporting visitors to the centre of the 1691 battle.</string>
    <string name="sites_description_gallery">The Luan Gallery is an publicly owned art gallery in Athlone, Westmeath, Ireland. The gallery opened in 2012, and the building consists of the older part, a former public library built in 1897 as a temperance hall, combined with a newer wing, designed by Keith Williams. The building was named Best Cultural Building of 2013 by the RIAI, and received a Civic Trust Award in 2014. To date, the gallery has hosted various shows including local, emerging artists such as Paul Quast and Séan Guinan, national upcoming talents as seen in the RDS Student Art Awards Travelling Exhibition, as well as established artists such as Catherina Hearne, Sinéad Ní Mhaonaigh and James Hanley RHA. The gallery takes its name from Luan son of Lugair son of Lugaid, a mythical chief who gives his name to the town.</string>
    <string name="sites_description_park">The Amenity Park at Dún na Sí is a newly created community park for all, encompassing ecology, arts, education and play. The area now covered by the Amenity Park was once a ‘commons’ used for grazing and was known locally as the ‘Cow Park’. Through the work of a local community group, the Midland Amenity Park Association, work began in 2008 to develop the area into a park and nature reserve. Five years later the transformation was complete and today you can enjoy a walk through planted parklands and a wetland reserve which is home to native wildlife species. A specially constructed ‘hide’ allows you to observe the many species of wild birds on the small lake or ‘turlough’ without disturbing their habitat.  With the ‘Art in the Park‘ project imaginative creations emerge from the parkland. These are made from recycled and natural materials by students from local schools who work with artists to enhance the visitors experience of the park. A fully equipped children’s playground is situated next to the Catoca Café which serves great coffee and offers an excellent lunch menu.</string>
    <string name="events_description_heal">10.00am – 5.30pm 15th July. At this two day workshop Yuan Tze, creator of Ren Xue philosophy and Yuan Gong Qigong, will delve into the root causes of peoples’ health problems and how to deal with them.</string>
    <string name="events_description_viking">Viking Ship sails daily from the quayside at Athlone Castle until the 4th Nov 2017. The Viking Longships have been sailing around our coasts since 795. The River Shannon is the main artery through the country and as we know the Vikings arrived by river in Clonmacnois in 842 which is 90 minutes downstream from Athlone and by ship is the perfect way to approach this famous monastic site. The Lough Ree Cruise (approx 75 minutes) goes upstream to the lake calling en route to the Hodson Bay and returns. Why don\'t you board the Viking Ship which departs from the quayside at Athlone Castle to Lough Ree the \'Lake of the Kings\' or check out our schedule to Clonmacnois.</string>
    <string name="events_description_gallery">29 April - 23 June. Luan Gallery presents its spring 2017 exhibition entitled ‘Elsewhere’. Featuring the works of three Athlone artists Elsewhere showcases the sterling talents of: Catherine Rock, Lawrence O’Neill and Lelia Henry. The exhibition is presented in 3 parts featuring three distinct exhibitions of work in painting, sculpture and drawing. Each artist occupies a solo space in the gallery with Catherine Rock’s abstract expressionist paintings housed in the New Gallery, Lawrence O’Neill’s 3D sculpted objects sitting along the River Gallery and Lelia Henry’s black and white charcoal drawings residing in the Library Gallery.</string>
    <string name="events_description_tri">8 July. Now in it’s 12th year the annual Waterways Ireland TriAthlone takes place on July 8th in Athlone. More than 500 athletes will be swimming the Shannon, cycling and running through the streets of the town with thousands of spectators cheering them on. Participants can tackle either the sprint or the Tri a Tri race either individually or as a relay team. Expect a fun festival atmosphere and a great afterparty at Karma! Not to be missed.</string>
    <string name="food_drink_description_seans">When you walk into Sean\'s Bar in Athlone, the oldest pub in Europe, you join the uncountable number of visitors who have been stopping here for a drink, a chat and maybe a bit of music for more than a thousand years and we have the distinctions to support it. No wonder, Sean\'s Bar is located in the very heart of Ireland, on the banks of the beautiful River Shannon at its intersection with the Esker Riada - the ancient route carved by glaciers that allowed travellers safe passage across the bog for thousands of years. You can find us just next to Athlone Castle, a 12th century Norman Castle whose residents may have frequented the pub! Just as popular today as it ever was, Sean\'s Bar is a must-see destination for people from every country in the world. Whether by boat, car, bus or train, people from every nation have come to \"have one\" in Sean\'s Bar. Walking into the pub, you\'ll know right away you\'ve arrived someplace unique. From the sawdust on the floor to the old-style open turf fireplace and the musicians playing in the corner, some things about Sean\'s Bar have changed very little over the centuries.</string>
    <string name="food_drink_description_karma">Opened in March 2005, Karma Athlone has become one of the best nightclubs in The Midlands. Located in the centre of Athlone, Co. Westmeath, Karma Athlone stands for simple ideas; to create a unique, comfortable, warm, enjoyable and safe clubbing environment for its customers. Here at Karma Athlone we open 5 nights a week, from Wednesday straight through to Sunday. Every week we welcome resident DJs to the club, DJ Bishop (Wednesday nights) DJ Alli B (Thursday nights) DJ Mark Wilson (Friday nights) and Karma legend DJ Dave G (Sunday nights) with our DJs varying every Saturday night to keep it fresh.</string>
    <string name="food_drink_description_thyme">Thyme was opened in November 2007 by John Coffey and his wife Tara with the idea of showcasing the talented and passionate local producers the midlands region and Ireland in general have to offer in a relaxed and comfortable setting. Thyme has gone from strength to strength over the years garnering many awards along the way. The food is best described as Modern Irish and is based on the seasons so menus will change accordingly. Situated in the heart of the historic town of Athlone, it is only a stones throw away from all the local attractions.</string>
    <string name="food_drink_description_bistro">Hatters Lane Bistro at Strand Street on Athlone’s Leinster shore is ideally located 3 minutes from the Town Bridge, Radisson, Prince of Wales and Sheraton hotels. The Hollywood themed bistro offers a welcoming cosy atmosphere with open fire, check table clothes, walls adorned with movie star icons. The background music is easy listening typically featuring tunes from Sinatra, Martin, Bennett and the likes.  Since opening in 1999, Hatter’s has established itself as a centre of high quality casual dining. Although renowned for a great steak the cuisine is continental and offers a comprehensive menu featuring fish, chicken, pasta and vegetarian dishes. The kitchen is always willing to accommodate various dietary requirements. Offering a la carte, value and set dinner menus, coupled with its private library room, it is ideal for all occasions.</string>
    <string name="stay_description_hodson"><![CDATA[At the Hodson Bay Hotel, you’re set for a fab family holiday in Athlone. Our family breaks include rooms with space to really relax and enjoy yourselves. We have also got an award winning kids club to entertain the little ones, whatever the weather. Our pool is perfect for a splashing time inside, and Ireland’s largest inflatable waterpark on our doorstep for some splashing outside. Everything from zip-lining to Greenway biking is just a short drive away. For a break that’s easy on your budget there are always great value packages on offer at The Hodson Bay Hotel. For the actively retired, ours is a home away from home. With packages between 2 and 5 nights, dedicated bowls, bridge and other themed breaks throughout the year, and a host of FREE activities at the hotel all year long such as Wine & Whiskey Tasting, Aqua Aerobics, Bingo, Craft Beer Tasting and Yoga. At Hodson Bay Hotel we\'ve got great value leisure… all taken care of.]]></string>
    <string name="stay_description_blu"><![CDATA[Our Radisson Blu Hotel provides a convenient and scenic accommodation for guests looking to enjoy all there is to see and do in Athlone. Stay within walking distance of the Athlone Marina, Athlone Castle and public bus and train stations. Along with a lovely riverfront setting, the hotel offers 128 rooms and suites with conveniences like 24-hour room service and Free high-speed, wireless Internet access.  For an upscale dining experience, visit the on-site Elements Bistro, where our chefs prepare delicious dishes in an eye-catching atmosphere donned in a theme of earth, wind and fire. Also onsite, the Quayside Bar & Lounge provides an elegant setting overlooking the water for sharing food, drinks and good conversation with colleagues or loved ones. After a full day of meetings or sightseeing, relax in the sauna, take a dip in the heated pool or work off stress at the fully equipped gym. Additionally, the hotel offers 10 professional meeting spaces suitable for both business or social gatherings of up to 650 guests.]]></string>
    <string name="stay_description_bandb">Shelmalier House is a family run bed and breakfast situated in a quiet location approx. 2km from Athlone town centre. It is a modern home surrounded by beautiful gardens and a barbeque area.  Our facilities include seven tastefully decorated en-suite bedrooms and each room is equipped with tv, direct dial telephone and tea/coffee making facilities. The gardens are large and our guests may sit, relax and enjoy the wide variety of shrubs and flowers planted in both gardens. Nancy and Jim Denby invite you to stay at Shelmalier House and experience hospitality with a difference!</string>
    <string name="stay_description_bay">Located along the shores of Lough Ree in Co. Roscommon just a short distance from Athlone and Roscommon town, Galey is an ideal location for outdoor pursuits, such as water sports, fishing, sailing, hunting, walking and cycling. Boat hire is available and canoe/kayak hire for groups can be organised. The park includes a range of facilities for guests, including a TV lounge, pool room, kitchen and children’s play area.</string>
</resources>
